<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Raghotham Sripadraj</title>
    <link>https://raghothams.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Raghotham Sripadraj</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 16:20:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://raghothams.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting for Humans</title>
      <link>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/hackathon-forecast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 16:20:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/hackathon-forecast/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For the past 3 years, I have had this idea of building a better forecasting system for business users. Business users mostly live on spreadsheets and the goal I had was to take advanced forecasting techniques to business users. Forecasting is one of the most challenging and hard problems in ML given the wide variety of domains it is applied to and the various ways available to solve this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalists</title>
      <link>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/generalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/generalists/</guid>
      <description>Traditionally, machine learning roles (in 2000s) were taken up by people mostly from research background. Their go-to toolkit would generally be R or Matlab because of the richness of algorithms offered by these programming languages. These solutions were intended to run on single compute instances. Slowly, these roles were taken by brilliant engineers who strongly believed in open source philosophy. They built algorithms in python which were easy to use and more accessible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/intro-neural-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/intro-neural-networks/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Neural Networks (ANNs) have totally changed what computers are capable of learning. Though neural networks date back 1940s, we are seeing an astonishing amount of increase of its applications in the recent 5–10 years.
Artificial neural networks are modeled on the functioning of the human brain, where the input is converted into output based on a series of transformations. Though they are capable of achieving complex tasks, the way they work is fairly straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raghothams.github.io/posts/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>I had zero knowledge about machine learning, but wanted to explore. I took up Large Scale Hierarchical Text Classification (LSHTC) as my Masters dissertation project, so that I have a good scenario to start Machine Learning
The first thing I wanted to know was the format of data provided by LSHTC. Turned out that it was SVM format. The training data and test data had the following format
label,label,label… feature:value feature:value</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>